iiit.ac.in 2017-02-15

# Privacy Policy | IIIT Hyderabad

The following policy applies to users of iiit.ac.in and is intended to explain what types of information is gathered from users and how that information is used.

The International Institute of Information Technology (IIIT-H) is committed to respecting your privacy. As an unregistered user, you can visit most of iiit.ac.in without revealing any personal information. We do not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily. Any personal information you choose to provide us will only be used by IIIT-H to conduct official IIIT-H business. IIIT-H does not sell, rent, loan, trade or lease personal information collected on this site.

For purposes of this policy, ''personal information'' means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.

### INFORMATION COLLECTED AND STORED AUTOMATICALLY

#### **Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of text placed on your computer by a web server. We occasionally use ''session'' cookies on some parts of iiit.ac.in to enhance your experience of the site and to help you move through it easily. Session cookies created on your computer by iiit.ac.in servers do not contain personal information. We may use a session cookie to store a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer. Session cookies are temporary and are automatically deleted during operation of your browser or when your browser is closed.

Most web browsers may be customized to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies. Rejecting or deleting cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this web site and could result in the loss of any customized setting.

#### **Logs and Network Monitoring**

We maintain log files of all access to iiit.ac.in and also monitor network traffic for purposes of site management and security. We use this information to help diagnose problems with the server and to carry out other administrative tasks. We also use log analysis tools for such purposes as creating summary statistics to determine which information is of most interest to users, identifying system problem areas, and determining technical requirements. The following information is typically collected in these files:

  * the Internet Protocol address and domain name of your Internet Service Provider and/or computer, if your computer has an IP address assigned directly to it;

  * the type of browser and operating system you use;

  * the date and time you visited iiit.ac.in;

  * the web pages or services you accessed at IIIT-H.edu and amount of time spent at each page; and

  * the web page from which you accessed iiit.ac.in and from which any page on this site was linked.

None of the foregoing information is deemed to constitute personal information per the Internet Privacy and Security Act.

### INFORMATION COLLECTED BY EMAIL AND ONLINE TRANSACTIONS

If you send us an email, we will collect your email address and the contents of your message. We will use your email address and the information included in your message to respond to you, to address the issues you identify, and to improve this web site. We may also use your email address to notify you about updates, services, special events or activities offered by iiit.ac.in.

If you complete a transaction such as an online application or an information request form, we will collect the information, including personal information, that you volunteered in completing the transaction. We will use this information only for the purposes for which the transaction was intended.

We may redirect your email message or information you provided through an online transaction to a IIIT-H office other than the one which originally received the message or information in order to better respond to you.

The information we collect is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video and graphic information formats included in the message or transaction.

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. You are cautioned, however, that we will treat personal information submitted in an email as though it was submitted by an adult, and it may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access.

### DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THIS WEB SITE

We may collect or disclose personal information without your consent if the collection or disclosure is:

  * necessary to perform IIIT-H's statutory duties or necessary to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or government statute or regulation;

  * made pursuant to a court order or by law;

  * for the purpose of validating your identity; or

  * of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in the form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.

Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through this website is subject to the provisions of the Information Technology Act (ITA) 2000.

We may also disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce IIIT-H's rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to IIIT-H's information technology assets.

### RETENTION OF INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THIS WEBSITE

We retain the information collected through this web site in accordance with the IIIT-H records retention and disposition policy. The retention period differs depending on the type of information collected. Questions regarding the records retention and disposition policy should be addressed to: query@iiit.ac.in.

### ACCESS TO AND CORRECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THIS WEBSITE

You may submit a request to the IIIT-H records access officer to determine whether personal information pertaining to you has been collected through this web site. Your request must be in made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of your identity. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to you, or similar appropriate identification.

### CONFIDENTIALITY AND INTEGRITY

We limit employee access to personal information collected through IIIT-H to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information.

In addition, we have implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of IIIT-H's information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of IIIT-H as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

For security purposes and to maintain the availability of IIIT-H for all users, we employ software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this web site.

### LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY SITES

iiit.ac.in may contain links to, and may be linked from, sites outside of IIIT-H. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, terms of use, or the content of such web sites. A link to an outside web site from iiit.ac.in does not constitute an endorsement or sponsorship of such web site or its content.

### CHANGES TO POLICY AND DISCLAIMER

We may change this policy from time to time, and reserve the right to do so without notice. The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through iiit.ac.in.

### CONTACT INFORMATION

For questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact: [query@iiit.ac.in](mailto:query@iiit.ac.in).

Page last updated on _18th November, 2015_
